How to create a 3D version in 3D space
Through the new 3D pen tool, you can directly create a 3D version in 3D space.
When clicking, press the Shift key to create a straight line.
On the created line, press the right key to select the length of the display or hidden line.
Press the P key to switch the drawing pen to a 3D version in 3D space.
When creating a line, press the Ctrl key and click to create a curve.
By editing the 3D pen tool, you can adjust the position of the straight line and the curve according to your needs.
When dividing the version by line,
the panels will automatically create a line of sewing along the shared division line.
When creating a line, press the D key.
You can switch the display to hide the created point away from the virtual model's distance.
You can based on the virtual model to draw some lines.
Then press the P key to continue to draw lines in 3D space to form a board.
Please adjust the board line by adjusting these points.
Press the right button to delete the board.
Press the right button to create a curve.
When the board looks as expected, use the cut screen as a board tool to create them.
Organize the board in the 2D window.
It can help you to understand the seam line relationship between the board and the board.
The sleeve board looks like it doesn't need to be separated, so we can combine them.
Use the sewing line and free sewing tool to sew the board together.
When the board on one side is finished, use the symmetrical board, board and sewing line tools.
When the board is finished, use the symmetrical board, board and sewing line tools.
Then sew the boards on both sides.
Model and check your clothing.
Adjust the board automatically and keep the jaw.
With the new advance of the automatic jaw tool.
Now the costume can automatically adjust its size and retain the same top structure, including the number of points and the order of the points.
First, add a virtual model.
Then add a costume.
Under the display environment menu, you can turn on the display statistics.
In the lower left corner of the screen, you can see all the statistics.
Now all the costumes have 3676 points.
Next, replace the virtual model with a child model.
You can open the display frame according to your needs.
This way, you can see more clearly how the costume is maintained after automatically adjusting the version.
Next, select the automatically adjusted version to support the top structure.
In the pop-up window, click on Maintain Top.
When the costume is re-dressed on the new virtual model, you can see that the number of costumes has not changed.
This function can also be used for your virtual model.
As long as you have applied the test suit information for your virtual model.
In the virtual model editor,
please make sure that your virtual model already has the test suit information.
Please make sure that the costume is simulated on the previous virtual model,
and record the test suit information of the virtual model to prevent errors in the automatically adjusted version.
Through the automatic adjustment version function,
we can quickly complete the costume use and configuration between different characters.
The order of the top of the grid will also be maintained when automatically adjusting the version.
For example,
three costumes that have been modified using the automatic adjustment version tool on different virtual models will be displayed.
In other software,
they can be deformed or mixed,
and there will be no errors.
Version generator
Through the measurement point or grass map,
you can quickly and easily create a costume in Marvelous Designer.
Click on the 2D version menu,
then select the version generator.
Next, please select the costume type.
Currently, it only supports the production of T-shirts,
and will add more options later.
Then,
according to the style you need to choose,
the T-shirt style is divided by the sleeve type.
Below, you will see the basic measurement data of the costume.
As for how to check and adjust your measurement data,
you have three different options.
The regular option will provide you with a complete list of the common measurement points of the costume.
The simple option will provide you with the most common measurement points,
to simplify the editing process.
The user's self-definition option allows you to customize your own measurement list,
and according to the required self-definition measurement data.
You can click on the eye icon
to select which costume versions to be created.
You can switch the version to symmetrical or left-right symmetrical.
The measurement options for all measurement options
can be used to display all measurement data for each version.
Click on the Detailed Information button.
You can switch to the list of all measurement information.
According to the measurement data that needs to be selected and displayed.
After the setting is complete,
click on the button to change the application.
Enter your version measurement value.
You can click on the reset button next to each measurement data
to restore it to its original value.
Some measurement items will contain a total length option
used to enter the total dimension of the front and back pieces.
Some measurement items also contain a pull-down option
used to select the measurement location applied to the measurement data.
You can click to display all measurement icons
to view all non-actual measurement items in each part.
Click on the Create button to create costumes in the 2D and 3D windows.
The AI version generator is available.
Using the data generated by the Marvelous Designer
will automatically generate measurement data.
To create a draft version for you,
click on the AI version generator button in the upper right corner of the version generator.
By entering the keyword to generate a picture
or directly upload a picture to generate the result,
select the type of costume,
and input your draft inspiration.
Please make sure to add as many descriptive words as possible.
If you want to emphasize some content, please put it in the brackets.
Currently only T-shape can be selected,
and more other styles will be introduced later.
A small tip, please try to provide words that describe accurately,
and not long sentences, to produce more effective results.
Clicking on the key word suggestion will display the power key word,
which will help you generate keywords.
Even if you use the same keyword, the AI picture will be re-created every time.
Therefore, clicking on the key word button
can keep the existing results as long as possible
while updating the key word.
According to the addition or change of the key word,
the result may be different from the existing result.
Clicking on the random generate button
will randomly add the power key word to the text prompt.
Click on the key word button,
click on the generate button to create a picture.
Click on the delete button to delete all input contents
and start creating again.
Click on the upload button to upload a reference image that meets the following guidelines.
Use the white background, black lines of the clothing draft
to ensure high-quality AI versions are generated.
Ensure that there are only clothing drafts in the image.
This process can be repeated until you get the desired result.
You can find the image history record generated by you on the right side of the window.
Self-designed model software simulation
Now software model simulation can be used for self-designed virtual models,
including simple non-human shapes or human virtual models without Google.
Software simulation can be used for OBJ and FBX virtual models.
Now add an OBJ or FBX virtual model.
Here we add an OBJ file,
then confirm the imported virtual model.
Please note that the imported virtual model
cannot have a hole or a self-interference problem.
Go to the virtual model rendering type in the 3D window.
Select semi-transparent surface or display frame to preview and check for potential problems.
Insert clothing that matches the size of the virtual model,
or create a set of clothing for the virtual model.
Now we have added a set of clothing.
Open the software model simulation option.
Select the virtual model and then go to the attribute editor.
You can select software model simulation under the surface.
Please remember to select CPU simulation and then open the simulation.
In this example,
we will adjust the software model strength to 6500.
Then speed up to see the final result.
In addition,
you can also apply software model simulation to simple structural objects.
In this example,
we are using a very simple object.
You can find it in the drawing library, virtual model, and fill-in model.
Please confirm again that your model has no hole or self-interference problem.
You can go to the 3D window and select semi-transparent surface.
You can also choose to open the frame display.
To see the cloth line more clearly and whether there is a gap.
Now we add fabric outside of this model.
Create a rectangular plate.
Put it on the virtual model.
Open the simulation and let it hang on the model.
Now we use the sewing tool to sew the two ends of this fabric together.
In this example,
we will reduce the particle diameter to 10,
then harden the plate.
Make the simulation more stable,
the effect is more obvious.
Select the model,
then open the software model simulation in the attribute editor.
Also remember to switch to CPU simulation,
then open the simulation.
Reduce the strength of the software model to 5000.
We will see the effect of the model under pressure.
Failure elimination.
If your virtual model has a gap or hole,
an error window will pop up.
In this example,
this model has a hole and insertion problem at the same time.
According to the conventional operation steps,
this model will be converted into a virtual model.
After loading,
we create a template to affect this model.
Then open the simulation,
simulate the fabric on the model.
If you try to use the software simulation function,
you will see the error prompt
and point out the current file problem.
We already know that
this file has two errors at the same time,
insertion and hole.
The prompt will also prompt the same error.
If you click OK,
it will turn off the spring,
cancel the activation of the software model simulation.
Therefore,
we recommend you again
to open the semi-transparent display
or open the display frame
to check whether there is a problem affecting the software simulation.
If you want to use software model simulation on this model,
then you need to solve the problem of hole and insertion first.
Then,
insert the file into Marvelous Designer again.
Boob water washing effect
Before this,
it has been a very complicated process
to create the boob water washing effect.
But using our new preset,
you can achieve this effect more quickly and more easily.
If you need to turn on the water washing effect,
please select the fabric to apply the effect first.
Then,
under the type selection,
switch the fabric from matte to boob.
Using this preset,
you can create many things.
Under the default setting,
it is set as for water washing,
but you can choose any water washing type or self-definition.
In this example,
I will choose acid washing.
As you can see,
the water washing effect has been successfully applied.
Now,
we can use some parameters to adjust the result.
The first one is acid concentration.
This is the only setting that changes according to the water washing type.
It controls the strength or opacity of the water washing sticker.
You can also adjust the mixing mode.
Here, I choose the mixing mode.
The absorption will increase the blur or spread effect for the sticker.
It mimics the way the water wash is soaked into the plant.
The cycle cycle can increase the brightness of the water wash.
It mimics the effect of a brighter world
with a longer water wash cycle.
Finally,
the boob powder can enhance the wrinkle texture
of the clothes.
You can try these parameters at will
to achieve the appearance you want.
Click on the water washing technique water washing pattern.
You can set the shrink,
rotate,
and balance of the water wash pattern.
You can enter specific parameters here
to make adjustments.
As mentioned above,
if you switch to a different water washing type,
you will see that the acid concentration has become another setting.
Their function is similar.
Try other water wash settings
to increase the authenticity of your work.
AI pose generator beta
Use keywords or reference pictures
to easily create a virtual model pose.
Click on the virtual model AI model pose generator beta
at the top of the menu.
You can enter keywords,
generate a reference picture,
or directly upload a reference picture.
First,
click on the reference picture.
Then,
directly upload a reference picture.
First,
select gender.
Click on the keywords.
Suggested keywords will be displayed.
To help you choose the right keywords,
click on the keywords.
Even if you use the same keywords,
the AI pose picture will be re-created every time.
Therefore,
click on the keywords button
to update the keywords at the same time.
As much as possible,
keep the existing results.
According to the keywords,
the results may be different from the current results.
Click on the keywords.
The system will provide the right keywords at random.
Enter words that describe the correct words
and not long sentences
to produce more effective results.
Then,
enter keywords.
Click on the generate button.
It will generate a pose according to your image.
Click on the keywords button.
The result will be generated.
The image displayed in the background is a reference picture of the uploaded picture.
Click the upload button to upload a picture that meets the following standards.
It is highly recommended to use full-body images from head to toe to ensure a high-quality AI posture.
Click the save button to transfer the generated posture to a POS file.
Now you can apply it to the virtual model you choose.
After creating a posture, you can turn on the display virtual model joints to adjust the posture.
You can also use the shortcut to open this option.
This is the highlight function of this update.
Please watch our subsequent updates to learn more.